<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | Jorand Gallou</title>
    <link>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jorandg.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Jorand Gallou© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jorandg.github.io/media/icon_hu7b5d921d9e091e22d2887ab6352bd001_137302_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Thesis on Path Planning</title>
      <link>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/master-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/master-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;truss-assembly&#34;&gt;Truss Assembly&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joint at the assembly nodes is a crucial part. For a robotic assembly, it is the part that requires the most advanced techniques, but it could be facilitated with a well engineered process. Different are discussed for the assembly of mirrors and then magnetic joints are presented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;assembly.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Bars Assembly&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;final-assembly.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Final assembly of 7 mirrors with the second design&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design ease the assembly for the robot. First, the grasping is made using magnetization so no need for special grasping. There is no lost surface and the bars are lighter which is a very important consideration for an on-­orbit assembly where the payload is very costly. Then because of the symmetry of the bars, the assembly needs to care only about the orientation of the element on the z axis. Finally, this design can easily be printed in space same as the ”Trusselator” which considerably reduces the payload for big structures assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;autonomous-path-planning&#34;&gt;Autonomous path planning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of steps is the number of modifications of the joint angle. The DQL showed good results. With this Policy, the robot could find the optimal path to the target with the minimum number of 3 steps. Finally, that technique was kept to make the Pick and Place environment where the robot had to catch a ball with a magnetized end-effector and place it in another desired position. In the end, the robot did it with an average of 5 steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Autonomous planning&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The EEZTbot with computer vision</title>
      <link>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/robot-arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/robot-arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to manipulate the MK1 we used an arduino uno and a joystick as you can see on the following picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;installation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Robot arm controller with a joystick&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The servos are plugged on the PWN pins 5, 6, 9. And the joystick is plugged on the A0 and A1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;conputer-vision&#34;&gt;Conputer Vision&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps are described on the github repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JorandG/EezybotMK1ComputerVision&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;EEZYbotComputerVision&lt;/a&gt; so that the user can obtain the postion of an object in a square made with aruco markers as followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cv.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Object detection&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Educational Robot: ilo</title>
      <link>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/ilo-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jorandg.github.io/publication/ilo-robot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cad-print.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;ilo CAD to Printed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;system-architecture&#34;&gt;System Architecture&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robot embeds common and open source components to be easily made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;architecture.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;ilo Architecture&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arduino is simply there to control the motors via the RAMPS 1.6, which is the motor shield. As a slave, it responds to a serial command of speed intensity on both translation and rotation possible on the ground. The raspberry is the master and controls all the actuators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mechanical-design&#34;&gt;Mechanical Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robot manufacturing tries to take advandage of 3D printing. This would allow for a greater sharing of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;facettes-print.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;ilo from every angle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the project aims to be open source, we try to make the robot fully 3D printable. &lt;a href=&#34;%22https://github.com/jumellet/ilo-bot/tree/main/parts%22&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; can be found the differnet parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;wheels.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;ilo Meccanum Wheels&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Meccanum wheels are the key part of the robot, and enable it to have 3 degrees of liberty on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;elementary-programming&#34;&gt;Elementary Programming&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal to introduce algorithm theory from the youngest age. We provide an easy way to learn how to structure computer code and execute it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;arrows.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;ilo Image Detection&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our system has the particularity to allow children to code without a computer. With a pencil and a sheet of paper, you can start to code the robot&amp;rsquo;s movements. The idea is to open the doors of programming as soon as possible and to as many people as possible. Verification the programming of the robot path is done with the application. It is simply a matter of taking a picture and ilo will start its journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
